Defy the Future
Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Mike Newell.
A rogue prince reluctantly joins forces with a mysterious princess and together, they race against dark forces to safeguard an ancient dagger
capable of releasing the Sands of Time – gift from the gods that can reverse time and allow its possessor to rule the world.
Prince Dastan, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Tamina, played by Gemma Arterton.
Nizam, played by Ben Kingsley.
Sheik Amar, played by Alfred Molina.
Seso, played by Steve Toussaint.
Garsiv, played by Toby Kebbell.
Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time is a 2010 action fantasy film based on the
video game series Prince of Persia created by Jordan Mechner.
It was directed by Mike Newell from a screenplay by Boaz Yakin, Doug
Miro, and Carlo Bernard, based on a story by Mechner.
The film stars Jake Gyllenhaal, Ben Kingsley, Gemma Arterton, and Alfred Molina.
It is an adaptation of the 2003 video game of the
same name published by Ubisoft.
Elements from its sequels Warrior Within (2004) and The
Two Thrones (2005) are also incorporated.
Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time premiered in London on May 9, 2010, and was released theatrically in the
United Kingdom on May 21 and the United States on May 28 by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and had grossed over $336.4 million on a production budget of $150–200
million, and was the highest-grossing video game film adaptation until it was surpassed by Warcraft in 2016.
The film explores themes of persia, sandstorm, brother
against brother, armageddon, based on video game.
The tone is dark.